If you want a fixed guaranteed income for your family for every month's expenses
, if you want a guaranteed source of income after your retirement, then this
plan will be very suitable for you. Hello friends, my name
is Anil Rajpurohit. I am the founder of Family First Financial Services, I am an MBA Finance
and have been working in the corporate sector for 15 years. And you are watching YouTube channel
Anil Rajpurohit Triple FS where you
get information about the best plans of life insurance, term insurance, health insurance, motor insurance on the channel. And today
I am presenting to you Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance's
Nischay Ayush Plan where you can get guaranteed income within 1 month of the premium increase
. That too tax free for the next 40 years and that too with insurance cover.
Watch this video completely. If you like the video, then definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel
and if possible, press the hype button. Let's understand the complete details of this plan.
In this plan, you are given five income variants which you
can select according to your different needs. The first variant is named
Level Income with Lumpsum Benefit. The second is Level Income with Enhanced Lumpsum Benefit. Here
you will get a higher maturity amount. The third is Increasing Income with Lumpsum
Benefit. Here your income will increase by 5% after every 5 year gap. The fourth
option is Level Income with Return of Premium Benefit. Here you
will get level income and the total premium you paid will be returned to you on maturity. And
the fifth option is Income Only Benefits. Here you will not get maturity
but you will get income in a slightly larger amount. If we look at the eligibility criteria of this plan,
then this is a non-linked non-participating plan. That is, it
is neither related to the stock market nor does it participate in the bonus. That is,
this is a 100% guaranteed plan. Here you
can purchase this policy for a 30-day-old child and a person up to 65 years can also purchase this policy.
The minimum maturity age in this will be 18 years. The maximum maturity age in this will remain 85.
Whole life option is also given. But it is probably not available for sale right now.
In future when it will be available, you will be able to take the option of whole life as well.
Talking about the premium payment term, here the fifth option is Income Only Benefit,
except this, the premium payment term in the first four options is 6, 8, 10 and
12 and if you want to take long term income, then you can take income from 15 years to 40 years
. You can select different income terms in different PPTs.
If you take the variant of Income Only Benefit, then here you can take income in 6 and 8
between 25 years to 40 years. But if the premium payment
term is 10 years or 12 years, then you will have to take a minimum term of 30 years. You
can take a policy term of up to 40 years. You can take income term. Here you
can pay the premium in yearly, semi-annually, quarterly and monthly mode.
Apart from the minimum premium income option in the policy
, if your entry in the first four options is from zero to 49 years and you
are taking 10 times insurance cover or seven times insurance cover
of your annual premium, then your minimum premium will be ₹3000. If you
want to take five times insurance cover, then it is not available. If your age is between 50 to 55.
In 10 and seven times, you can purchase the policy with a premium of ₹30000 only. If you
want to take five times insurance cover, then you can purchase the policy with a premium of ₹1 lakh
. If your age is between 56 years to 65 years, then you
will get the option of 5 times and 7 times insurance cover only and there you
can purchase the policy with a minimum premium of ₹ 1 lakh. In income only benefit, if your age
is between zero to 45, then the premium will be ₹ 50000. If you are between 45 to 49, then the
premium will be ₹ 1 lakh. If you take 10 times or 7 times insurance cover and if your
age is between 56 to 60, then you can purchase the policy with a premium of ₹ 1 lakh.
Where you can take insurance five times or seven times. Now let us assume that
the benefit of 10 times insurance is that the income coming from it
remains tax free. Seven times and five times income is taxable. But if you do not fall in the taxable income
tax slab. Now let's assume that
income up to ₹12 lakh is not taxed. So you can take five times the insurance cover.
Suppose you already have a term plan running and you don't want to take any more insurance.
If I need a sum of money but I want a big income, then you can take a five times insurance cover,
then your incoming income will be a little more or you can
also see the minimum sum assured on the table that the minimum sum assured is from 3 lakhs to 5 lakhs, you
can take it according to how many times insurance cover you want to take according to this table
. Talking about death benefit, in this policy, the death benefit
will be higher of sum assured on death or surrender benefit. Sum Assured and Death means
sum assured or 105% of total premium paid. Sum Assured here means five
times, seven times or 10 times whatever you select for insurance
. Apart from this, you are also given the option of staggered death benefit. It means
that when death occurs, you do not want to take the money at once but
over the period of 5 years. You
can take it in annual mode as well as in monthly mode. So in this way, if you want to take it in installments instead of taking it all at once,
then you can take the death benefit. Talking about
survival benefit, in all the different options,
you will keep getting a certain portion of income in front of your annual premium, which
will depend on your age, income premium, policy term and premium payment term. We
will explain in detail how much income will come in which option. In this policy, you will get a maturity benefit in every variant
except the fifth variant. The maturity
benefit will be a guaranteed lump sum benefit which will depend on your policy term, premium payment term,
your age and different things. So according to that factor,
you will also get the maturity amount according to the total premiums you have paid.
I am going to tell you this maturity amount in detail in the illustration as well.
Now let us understand all the options with benefit illustration.
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited The name of the plan is AB SLI
Fixed Ayush Plan Non Linked Non Participating Individual Saving Life
Insurance Plan. The age of a customer is 35 years whose name is Anil Rajput.
Here he is paying premium for 12 years. He
is taking a policy term of 40 years. He is selecting the deferment period as zero year. He
will pay premium in annual mode. His GST will be 4.5% in the first year. From the second year it will be 2%.
He is paying ₹ 1 lakh in annual premium. He
is not an employee of Aditya Birla's online company. He is not getting any discount. If you
had an already existing policy in Birla, you would have got a discount of around 12%
for the first year. Your insurance cover here will be ₹ 1 lakh.
The factor of income benefit is 39.45. And the income you are taking
is annually and in arrears, not in advance, which means
you want to take it after the completion of the year. The name of the option is Level Income with Lumpsum Benefit.
You have taken the long term variant of income. You are paying Rs. 1 lakh premium annually.
With GST you have to pay Rs. 104500. Then you
will have to pay Rs. 102250 from the second year onwards. I have not selected the rider here. If you want to do it, you
can do it according to your need. You will see here that
you are paying premium in the beginning of the year. You are paying premium for 12 years.
At the end of the year, you will get an income of Rs. 39,450 on which guarantee will be written and this
income will keep coming to you for the entire 40 years and on maturity of the policy you will get maturity benefit of Rs. 16,80,000
on which guarantee will also be written. You can check the total
benefit here. Your death benefit
will be ₹ 1 lakh from the first year itself, which will keep increasing up to ₹ 12,60000. Sir, you
can also check the Guaranteed Surrender Benefit here in this column, that in which year you will surrender value, how much surrender
benefit you will get. It is special surrender value. The company declares it. So,
if you surrender, you will get the higher amount out of Guaranteed Surrender Value and Special Surrender Value
. You can also take a loan up to 80% of the surrender value.
Now, there is a 35 year old person, he pays premium for 12 years.
He takes the policy term as 40 years. Option number one is Level Income with Lumpsum Benefit. There if he
pays an annual premium of ₹1 lakh and takes zero deferment period and there he
takes income in arrears, then he will get an income
of ₹39450 for 40 years and at the end of the policy he will get ₹1680000 on maturity. If he
takes a deferment period of one year, then he will get an income
of ₹45700. If he takes a deferment period of 2 years, then he will get an income of ₹49,350. In a 3-year reference period, he will get
an income of ₹53,900, in a 4-year deferment period, he will
get an income of ₹58450 and if he takes a 5-year reference period, he will get an income of ₹63,700 and
On maturity you will get ₹16,80,000. So now you have to take the income from the first year,
from the second year, from the third year, annually, in monthly mode. You
can take it according to your convenience. For example, a customer
purchases the policy on 25 July 2025 and selects it in arrears. That means he will get the income after the completion of the year
. So his first income will come on 25 July 2026. If he takes a one-year deferment period,
then he will start getting income on 25 July 2027. In this way,
you can also select the option of advance. So you will get income in advance.
You will get income within a month of purchasing the policy. That means you will start getting income even before the year starts
. So that income will be a little less. But after the end of the year,
if you take the income option, the air option, then
you will get a little more income here.
Now let's see option number two
, which is called level income with enhanced lump sum benefit. Same premium, everything
is kept the same. What will be the only difference? Your income here will be 38,050 because you
are getting a higher maturity here. Instead of 1680000, you
are getting a maturity of ₹24 lakh. Enhanced lump sum option number two, a 35-year-old person will pay premium for 12 years.
The policy term is 40 years. He pays ₹1 lakh premium. In the zero deferment period,
an income of ₹38050 will come. The maturity will be ₹24 lakh. Because the name of this option is enhanced lump sum.
So the maturity here, which was ₹16,80,000 in the first option. In this option
, you will get ₹24 lakh. So the income will seem a little less here. So now you
have to decide whether you want more income or more maturity.
You can see on the screen here
how much income you will get on the deferment period as per your different needs and for how many years. Now let's see option number three, everything
is the same. Customer premium, payment term, policy term, everything is the same. The name of the option is
Increasing Income with Lumpsum Benefit. So here from the first year you
will get an income of ₹37450 which will remain the same for 5 years. Then it will increase by 5% to 39323.
Then it will remain the same for the next 5 years. Then your income will be 41195 which
will remain the same for the next 5 years. In this way, your income will keep increasing
to ₹50558 in every 5 years gap and you will get ₹16,80,000 on maturity. Insurance
cover will also be there from day one and this income will be tax free for you.
You can also see surrender benefit and if you want, you can take a loan on this. Option number
three Increasing income with lump sum benefit Age 35 Premium will be paid for 12 years. Policy term
is 40 years. Premium is paid at ₹1 lakh. Defun period of zero years is taken. So
in the first year, they will get an income of ₹37,450 and this will keep increasing at a simple interest rate of 5% every 5 years
. Which will keep increasing
to ₹50,558. You will get ₹16,80,000 on maturity. So now you can see on the screen here
that how much income you will get
from the first year to the last year if you take a depreciation period of how many years . Now let's see option number four which
is an option with many companies where you get an income and
return of premium benefit. So now here you will see that
you paid a premium of ₹1 lakh and at the end of the first year, you got an income of ₹41450. So only about
₹58,000 something got invested from your pocket. The rest you got is tax free income and in addition to this
you are also getting insurance cover. So you will keep getting this income from the first year itself and
this income will come for the entire 40 years and later you will also get a refund of your ₹12 lakh deposited
. If you want, you can take this income in monthly mode also. You may also want to select this
in advance mode that before the completion of the whole year, if I
want the income in this year itself, that is, if you want income in 2025 only, then also you can take it.
The income amount will be reduced a little but you can select this advance option also
. Let's see Option number Four Level Income with Return of Premium Benefit Age 35
Premium Payment 12 years Policy term 40 years Premium of ₹1 lakh Deferred If
you take zero year, then you will get an income of ₹41450. You will get ₹12 lakh on maturity
. Here is return of premium. Meaning the premium that you are paying of
₹12 lakh in 12 years will be refunded to you. But if you look at the income, from the first year itself you
are getting a guaranteed tax free income of ₹41450 per lakh, that too
with insurance cover. If you are taking a deferment period of one year, then
you are getting an income of ₹48200, which means for the next 39 years you
will get an income of ₹48200. If you are taking a deferment period of 2 years, then you will get ₹51850 for 38 years and
You will get a tax free guaranteed maturity of ₹12 lakhs. Here you
can take a premium of ₹50000 as well. If you pay a premium of 5 lakhs, then the income on that will also
be tax free.
Now let's see the last option. This option is called
Income Only Benefit. In Income Only Benefit, you pay ₹1 lakh for 10 years. There
is no option of 12 years in this option. Here you will get an income of ₹43,200 and
you will not get any amount on maturity. You will only get income
. Here 10 years are being made. You will start getting income of ₹43,200 from the first year
for the next 40 years. Option number five is Income Only Benefit in which
you will not get maturity. You will only get income. Here the premium payment is not for 12 years.
It is only for 10 years. I have taken the policy term of 40 years. If the deferment period is zero, then
you will get an income of ₹43,200. Because the premium has to be paid only for 10 years and here
only income will come. There will be no maturity income. In a deferment period of one year,
you will get an income of ₹47,800 and
if you take a deferment period of 5 years, then you will get an income of ₹67,300 for the next 35 years. Now here in the summary, you
can see four or five options, how much income comes on which deferment period.
In which option and how much maturity comes. Like for example,
option number one, you took a deferment period of two years. You will get an income of ₹49,350.
Maturity will be ₹16,80,000. Option number two is a deferment period of two years.
You will get an income of ₹45,300 . But the maturity is 24 lakhs. Option number three: If the deferment
period is 2 years, then from the first year you will get an income of ₹44,550. It will increase by 5% every 5 years.
It will increase to ₹60143 and you will get ₹16,80,000 on maturity.
If you take the option of Level Income with ROP, then you will get an income of ₹51,850 in the deferment period of 2 years.
For the next 38 years and 12 years, you will get ₹12 lakh on maturity
. If you take income only benefit and pay premium for only 10 years,
you will get an income of ₹51600 for the next 38 years and that and the insurance cover will also be yours and all this
income will be tax free. You will also get the benefit of ATC and you will also
get the benefit of 1010D. Regarding the riders, here you will get five riders. One
is the rider for accidental benefit, which means that whatever amount of sum assured you add in
the accidental benefit rider, that much additional insurance cover you will get. At the time of death, if you
select the option of the rider of waiver of premium rider, that means suppose
you get a critical illness or if you become permanently disabled in an accident,
then the increase in premium is waived. The benefits continue. Or if
the proposer is you and the life insured is your son who is a minor, in that case if
something happens to you, then the remaining premiums will be waived and the policy
will continue for the son. The name of the third rider option is Critical Illness Benefit
Rider. Here you will get four critical illnesses covered in the policy. Like
stroke, cancer, heart attack or any major organ transplant. In this way
four critical illness benefits will be added in this policy. So whatever sum assured
you add in this rider, if any of these diseases is diagnosed, you
will get lump sum benefit at once. Talking about hospital care rider, here
if you get admitted in the hospital, you can get hospital care ranging
from ₹600 to ₹6000 per day . If you get admitted in ICU, you
will get additional money. This much amount is normally between ₹600 to ₹6000
. Talking about surgical care rider, here you
will get surgery amount up to ₹3000 per day. So you can also take this surgery option.
These are all riders which you get under additional premium.
As for the other benefits of the policy, here you will get both the benefits of surrender and RPO in the policy
. If you want to surrender the policy, then after 2 years the surrender value
is generated or you can also get it reduced. Where you
will continue to get your benefits in the proportion in which you paid the premium.
In this policy, you will also get a loan up to 80% of the surrender value. Tax benefit
In section 8C of Income Tax, you have a tax benefit of up to ₹ 1.5 lakh and in 1010D you
will get tax free income. Talking about the free look period, here you
have been given a pre-look period of 15 days. If for any reason you want to cancel the policy, then you can get a free look in the company
. Talking about the revival period. If for any reason you
are unable to pay the premium on time for 1 year or 2 years, then you get a revival period of 5 years.
Yes. You can continue the policy by
paying premiums for the number of years for which you were not able to pay premiums in one go
. So finally if I summarize this plan , it is a great plan which gives you long term guaranteed income. That too
from the first month. You can take income for 15 years as per your requirement. You
can also take income for 40 years. It is possible that in future you may also get the option of whole life
. Here you also have the option of premium payment term. You can take income for
40 years even after paying premium for six years . You can also
take income for 40 years even after paying premium for 12 years. You can take level income. You can take maturity benefit. So
if you want to take income in increasing mode, you can do so. You can take different riders.
Like waiver and premium rider, if you have taken the policy in the name of the child and
if something happens to the proposer, then this income will continue to come to the child.
So very good features have been given in it. Keeping in mind different needs,
you have also been given different income options. So if you
want to purchase this plan from me, then you can consult on the number given below. If you like the video,
then before leaving, please subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit Triple FS
. If possible, also press the hype button so that this video reaches as many people as possible
and they can purchase a good income plan for their every month. Whoever wants
a guaranteed income or even for retirement, if they want a settled income so that
they keep getting a fixed income, then there is a very good plan for them too. Thank you so
much. Jai Hind.